adorama.com 2018-10-03

# 

Adorama’s pledge to you:

Adorama respects your privacy. To better protect your privacy we provide this privacy policy explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. This privacy policy applies to the Adorama web site, located at www.adorama.com.

**Adorama will:**

  * NOT sell, rent, or lease your personal information  

  * NOT keep you on our mailing lists if you have requested to be removed  

  * NOT share your information with any trading partners unless you have requested information, products, or services that can be best handled by another company 

**Adorama will:**

  * Treat your privacy very seriously and will adhere to this Privacy Policy  

  * Promote this Privacy Policy internally so all employees abide by it  

  * Keep this Privacy Policy accurate.

Adorama is one of the nation's largest photo retail and mail order suppliers. For over 25 years we have been serving professionals as well as amateurs in the photographic, video, digital imaging and telescope fields. We offer the best combination of quality services, vast selection, knowledgeable staff, and competitive pricing.

_Types of information we collect_  
_How we use your information_  
_Children and personally identifiable information_  
_Access, accuracy and opt-out rights_  
_Security_  
_Third Party Websites_  
_Third Party Cookie Integration_  
_First Party Cookie Integration_  
_Other important information_

Types of information we collect: 

There are two types of information that Adorama collects online: (1) personally identifiable information supplied by visitors to our web site, and (2) non-personal information gathered as visitors navigate through the web site. 

**Personally Identifiable Information**  
Personally identifiable information is information that can be directly associated with a specific person or entity, such as name, address, or email address. Adorama collects personally identifiable information from site visitors in the following instances:

  * When you place an order on our site, we require you to provide your name, email address, mailing address, telephone number and credit card information. 
  * At the time of ordering, you may also choose to register by creating a user name and password. By registering, you create a user profile which allows us to customize your experience on this web site, as well as provide a faster method for you to submit a request for information to www.adorama.com and receive back either the information or products desired.
  * When you voluntarily provide us with your information via a web form on our web site, or while corresponding with us via email.

It is not necessary to provide any personally identifiable information in order to simply browse our web site.

**Non-Personal Information**  
Adorama routinely gathers non-personal information, including how many people visit this web site, the pages they visit, where they come from, how long they stay, their IP address, and the type of browser they used while visiting. None of this information is used to identify you personally.

Non-personal information is gathered through the use of cookies, web beacons and web server logs.

  * A cookie is a small piece of information that a web site sends to a visitor's computer and which is then stored on the visitor's hard drive. 
  * A Web beacon is an electronic image, also known as a clear GIF or a single-pixel (1x1). Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on a visitor's computer, such as a visitor's cookie number, the time and date of a page view, and a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed. You may render some Web beacons unusable by rejecting their associated cookies.
  * A web server log is a file where web site activity is stored. Every time a visitor requests a file or web page an entry is made into our server logs. These files include the HTML files and their imbedded graphic images and any other associated files that are transmitted to Web site visitors. Log files can be analyzed and summarized by another program.

Although Adorama uses web server logs, web beacons, and cookies on this web site, we do not know who any visitor is unless that person specifically tells us.

How we use your information 

**Non-Personal Information**  
Adorama typically uses the non-personal information we collect in order to better understand how you and other visitors use our web site, for system administration, to confirm that you’ve opened the emails that we send you, and to customize your experience when using this web site. For example, we use cookies to ensure that items added to your shopping cart during one visit are accessible to you on subsequent visits until you either place an order or delete the items from the shopping cart.

**Personally Identifiable Information**  
Adorama may share your personally identifiable information with trusted third party vendors for the sole purpose of facilitating your order. For example, we provide your name, shipping address, phone number, and order information to our shipping carrier. We also may provide your name, billing address, and credit card information to the credit card processor that facilitates the transaction. Adorama has strict guidelines requiring all third parties to keep any shared personally identifiable information confidential.

Unless otherwise required by law, or if pertinent to a judicial or governmental investigation, or as voluntarily released by you, your personally identifiable information is not shared with other organizations or persons, other than to organizations or persons assisting us in collecting, assembling or processing this information.

In the course of growing or restructuring our business, we may purchase the assets of another company or sell the assets of our company. During these transactions, information about customers is frequently considered a business asset that is the subject of such a purchase or sale. Also, in the unlikely event that Adorama, or substantially all of its assets are either acquired or subject to liquidation in bankruptcy, information may be transferred as well. We will require third parties who obtain access to your information as a result of a transaction to adhere to this privacy policy as a condition to transferring the information to them.

Children and personally identifiable information 

This web site is designed for those 15 years of age and older. We will not knowingly collect information of any kind from anyone under the age of 13. If we become aware of a visitor under the age of 13 providing information on our site, we will terminate any accounts associated with that visitor and purge our databases of all information provided by that visitor.

Access, accuracy and opt-out rights

Adorama will make every effort to provide you with access to your personally identifiable information so that you may review, update or correct that information. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before enabling you to view your data and/or make corrections. If you have submitted personally identifiable information to Adorama and would like it removed or modified, please contact us at [info@adorama.com](mailto:info@adorama.com). We will use reasonable efforts to comply with your request.

If you don’t want Adorama to gather non-personal information about you and/or place cookies onto your desktop, you can generally change your cookie and other security settings on your web browser. For more information, please consult your web browser documentation. Please keep in mind that if you choose to prevent Adorama from placing cookies onto your desktop, you may not be able to enjoy the full functionality of this web site.

If you have registered on this web site, your personally identifiable information relating to you and your order history are available to you. However, each time you log into your account on this web site, you will be required to provide the password that you created at the time you registered. After providing your password, you can edit or delete your information at any time through the "Account info" page.

We will also provide you the opportunity to opt-out at any time of certain or all contact from Adorama, and we will do everything we can to honor such requests. This choice will generally be offered at the bottom of our on-line or off-line communications to you. If you have any difficulty exercising your choices, please contact us at [info@adorama.com](mailto:info@adorama.com), or you may contact us via the following methods:

**By Mail:**  
Adorama Inc.  
42 West 18th Street  
New York, NY 10011

**By Phone:**  
Toll Free: 1 (800) 223-2500 (US and Canada)  
Local or international: (212) 741-0052

**By Fax:**  
(212) 463-7223

Security 

The security of your information is very important to us. Adorama follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We use state-of-the-art data encryption technology to protect against loss, misuse or alteration of your user information. Secure Socket Layers (SSLs) encrypt the information sent between your computer and our database. Our ordering system is certified by Verisign, an internet leader in security transactions. In addition, we use Internet fraud screening to protect credit card transactions.

To be sure you're browsing secure pages, check your Web browser's status bar (located at the bottom of the window) for the closed padlock icon. This icon appears in the latest versions of Internet Explorer and Netscape Navigator to tell you that you are viewing a secure web page. Also, all browsers display an "s" after the "http" (https://..) in the Web site address to indicate that you're in a secure environment.

**Credit Card Fraud Warranty**  
We guarantee that every online transaction you make will be 100% safe. This means you pay nothing if unauthorized charges are made to your card as a result of shopping at our online store. Under the Fair Credit Billing Act, your bank generally cannot hold you liable for more than $50.00 of fraudulent charges. If your bank does hold you liable for any of this $50.00, we will cover the entire liability for you, up to the full $50.00. We will only cover this liability if the unauthorized use of your credit card resulted through no fault of your own from purchases made while using the secure server. In the event of unauthorized use of your credit card, you must notify your credit card provider in accordance with its reporting rules and procedures.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, please contact [info@adorama.com](mailto:info@adorama.com).

Third Party Websites

The Adorama web site may contain links to other sites. We do not endorse or otherwise accept responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those sites.

Adorama may share your personally identifiable information with trusted third party vendors for the sole purpose of facilitating your order. For example, we provide your name, shipping address, phone number, and order information to our shipping carrier. We also may provide your name, billing address, and credit card information to the credit card processor that facilitates the transaction. We also may grant limited access to your name and email address to the agency that deploys emails and other marketing campaigns on our behalf for the purpose of improving our marketing outreach programs. Adorama has strict guidelines requiring all third parties to keep any shared personally identifiable information confidential.

Third Party Cookie Integration

We may use third party companies to provide advertising services and/or to collect certain information when you visit and interact with our website. These third-party companies may collect and use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visit to this website [and/or other websites] in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. 

These third-party companies may use cookies and other technologies to recognize your browser to collect and record information about your web surfing activity including your activities on this website. You may visit the Network Advertising Initiative, [networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) or the Digital Advertising Alliance, [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/), to learn more about interest-based advertising, or to opt out of receiving advertisements tailored to your interests on your browser, from their respective members and participants.

First Party Cookie Integration

We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with relevant online display advertising tailored to your interests. 

To opt out of our cookies used for this online advertising, [please click here.](http://dtmc.adorama.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=62275&cname=Adorama&cmagic=960e27&clogo=62275.png&loc=us&lang=en-us)

Other important information 

If you have any questions that are not answered by this policy, or would like more information about any aspect of this policy, please contact us at [info@adorama.com](mailto:info@adorama.com).

Adorama reserves the right to modify this privacy policy at any time. We will promptly reflect any such modifications on this privacy policy.

This privacy policy was last updated on: June 15, 2018
